

IVÁN FELIPE PÉREZ TORRES

JAVA SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT



(+57) 3046563937



Bello, Antioquia



ivanfelipeprz@gmail.com

ABOUT ME

Professional, self-taught, and analytical software developer with a background in software development in the Back End side with more than 5 years of experience using 00P languages mainly in Java (with Spring boot) and others like Python (with Django), Kotlin and Scripting techniques. Enhances the quality of software by implementing software architecture practices, clean code principles, and unit testing practices to guarantee quality, efficiency, readability, and scalability of software. Has contributed to projects for different sectors like BPO & Contact centers, industrial, social, and financial industries. Believes in sharing knowledge as a tool to foster and encourage the team members to increase the quality and the pace of the team.







TECH SKILLS

Databases managing
CD/CI awareness
Work tracking
Debugging techniques
Code reviewing
Unit & Integration testing
Refactoring
Clean code techniques
Object-oriented programming
Bug fixing
Agile methodologies adaptability
Pair programming
Performance focused
Algorithmic thinking
Source code control

SOFT SKILLS

Teamwork
Knowledge sharing
Analytical thinking
Communication
Customer-focused
Creativity
Conflict resolution
Problem-solving
Self-development
Self-awareness
Team-awareness
Responsibility
Work-ethic
Commitment

Innovation



SKILLS

INTERESTS

- Java
- Spring boot
- Object oriented programming
- Aspect Oriented Programming
- Functional programming
- Unit testing
- Scripting
- Web scrapping
- Clean code and architecture practices
- Debugging techniques
- Microservices architecture
- Git
- Code review
- Relational database engines
- SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL, MSQL server)
- Cache
- Logging
- AWS (Kinesis, Cloudwatch, EC2)
- Monitoring metrics (Datadog)
- Support (Bug fixing)
- Agile Methodologies
- SCRUM
- KANBAN
- SCRUMBAN
- JIRA
- Knowledge sharing
- Pair programming
- Risk awareness



Technology: Researching new knowledge about software development.



Language: Speaking
Spanish fluently. Highly
motivated to keep
improving English skills.
Sharing in cultural
interchange academies
locally with foreigners to
meet new cultures. Reading
and watching English
content and resources.



Education: Self-starter, Self-taught, teach with passion. Reading selfdevelopment books, leadership books, and financial education books.



Sports: Riding bike, running, watching american football.



Music: Listening to different kind of genres of music as local music and foreigner music. Listening to music and podcasts to improve English Skills



Social: Sharing time with family and friends.
Respectul, friendly, funny, open mind at moment to meeting new people and making new friends

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE TESTER - JANUARY 2015 TO JULY 2015 EMTELCO / BPO & CONTACT CENTER / SOFTWARE ENGINEERING AREA

- Analyze related documentation about the application to test like software requirements and related documentation hosted in Enterprise Architect tool.
- Analyze IVR workflows and software requirements to design test plans and test cases.
- Design test plans composed of the scope, risk factors, execution prerequisites, and strategy for general the applications like IVR, CRM, and Reports developed in the engineering and development area.
- Design the closing report at the end of the test process.
- Manage bugs founded during the execution of the test cases in the Mantis Bug Tracker System.
- Create user manuals for the tested general applications.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - SEPTEMBER 2015 TO SEPTEMBER 2019 SIMAC SAS / INDUSTRIAL SECTOR / SOFTWARE ENGINERING AREA



- Make techinical decisions.
- Develop software applications to automate processes by scripting techniques with Python, Java, VBScript, SQL, RPA to integrate data in database storage.
- Create Reports and Stored Procedures in SQL Server and reporting services to handle data and create stats reports.
- Implemented new software techniques in the team.
- Increase sales developing new and innovative projects/services for companies in the industrial sector.
- Stepped in on innovative projects using RPA techniques to automate processes and scripting skills to develop new integrations.
- Collaborate closely with other software developers and industrial engineers to integrate systems with structured information (databases, spreadsheets, etc.) or unstructured information(emails, documents, etc).
- Increase the knowledge base of the company in the software area like manuals, guidelines or repositories.
- Managed cloud servers for the applications in Amazon Web Services using EC2.

JAVA SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - SEPTEMBER 2019 TO JUNE 2021 GLOBANT

Globant >

- Support microservices written in Java using Spring Boot framework.
- Implement new software features with multiple technologies in different software components (graph databases, relational databases, AWS kinesis, Redis cache).
- Support legacy code attending client issues categorized in level 3.
- Pay off technical debt in services applying best practices to code like refactoring, source code control (git), debugging techniques, code reviewing, and test coverage.
- Worked with scrum, kanban and scrumban methodologies to track and estimate features and bugs.

2015

2015 2019

20192021

WORK EXPERIENCE

JAVA SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - JUNE 2021 TO AUGUST 2023 EPAM SYSTEMS / FINANCIAL PROJECT / SOFTWARE ENGINEERING



- Worked with Scrum Framework in at least a 10-person team.
- Support legacy code in dockerized microservices written in Java, Spring boot, and Kotlin in an event architecture with Kafka.
- Applied best practices to code like refactoring, source code control (GitLab).
- Peer review in code and QA/Testing notes.
- Dev Testing/Writing QA/Testing notes results due to QA members absence within the team.
- Watch/Monitoring metrics to identify latency spikes and fix bugs using Datadog and Kibana.
- Ramping up new team members to the project.

2021 2023

EDUCATION

POLITÉCNICO COLOMBIANO JAIME ISAZA CADAVID

• Graduated of Professional technique in programming in information systems (with honors)



2012 2015

INTELLIGENT TRAINING

• Certified of Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3



2013

ALIANZA FUTURO DIGITAL MEDELLÍN

 Certified acceleration course - MVA (Microsoft Virtual Academy)





2013

CORPORACIÓN UNIFICADA NACIONAL DE EDUCACIÓN SUPERIOR CUN Y COLNODO SUPPORTED BY GOOGLE

• Certified of Management of Local Information Systems





2015

POLITÉCNICO COLOMBIANO JAIME ISAZA CADAVID

• Graduated of Technology in data systematization (with honors)



2015 2017